What's with that outfit?
We're going potato picking at the Nursery today!
Where did you see something like that?
According to the magazine at the convenience store,
Future of Agriculture
everyone dresses like this
when they work in the fields.
Do you plan on digging up
potatoes with a bug catching net?!
Kobato.
How do I do this again?
The simplest things in life
end up being the most difficult.
I just want to smile when I'm happy
and sing a song whenever I please.
I was told, "Someday,
your dream will come true."
But when exactly will that be?
I can't wait that long!
I spread my arms
on the count of one two three
and gather all the light in the world.
Tell me,
isn't there something I can do?
Even if someone hurts my feelings,
I'll keep running toward the light.
Even if I trip, fall, and cry my eyes out, I still believe.
Although it may seem silly...
I believe in tomorrow.
Production
The Kobato Protection Group
...What Twilight Sought After.
Thank you for taking care of us again this year.
Think nothing of it. Pick as many as you would like!
Thank you!
Listen up.
You carry the potatoes that you dig up.
So only dig up as many as you can carry, got it?
Kobato, look it! They're connected!
Look how big it is!
Wow!
This is like treasure hunting, isn't it?
Ouch...
Wow!
It's so big!
So cool!
Do... Dobato!
Kobato, your back is covered in dirt.
Huh?
I wonder who that could be...
He's a little older than the
children at Yomogi Nursery.
I wonder if he lives here?
No, the lady's grandchild who lives
here is already a high school student.
Then...
I wonder where this child is from.
Hey.
Are you here by yourself?
Do you live nearby?
Wait!
I'm sorry. We didn't notice him in time.
It's all right. These things happen once in a while.
I wonder if he's one of the neighbor's children...
All right then. It's about time we clean up and head back!
Okay!
You sure dug up a lot, didn't you?
Kobato!
That's so many potatoes...
I tried my best!
Hey.
I believe I said this when we first started.
You carry what you dig up.
Well, I guess we're having baked potatoes when we get back.
Yay!
Kobato, will you be okay?
Should we help you carry some?
No, I'll be okay! I can carry them all by myself!
It's impossible for you to carry
that many by yourself. I'll help too.
No, it's okay! The agreement was for you to carry all the potatoes that you dug up.
Of course it was.
He's still such a bully...
I-It's not possible... give it up, Kobato.
Missy!
We'll help you.
Really?
Thank you so much.
Are they done yet?
There's so much smoke!
Is it hot?
Here you go.
Thank you!
It's hot so be careful, okay?
Hey!
Here you are.
Yum...!
What are we going to do about this?
Should I bake some more?
Yes, let's share some with the neighbors!
Fujimoto? Could you take Kobato with you to those houses?
I'll go by myself.
It'll be faster that way.
But... Oh, together is just better.
I want you to get to know the neighbors better too.
Is that okay with you, Kobato?
Yes!
I'll... do my best!
Don't ask me to help you. And don't be a hindrance.
My potatoes!
He really is a bully. He
always says I'm a hinderance...
But despite that, he never says don't come with me, does he?
But he took my potatoes! I thought I was going to deliver them myself.
You could see it as them being too heavy.
So he decided to do you a favor by carrying them for you, no?
Yes?
We're from Yomogi Nursery.
We went potato picking today, so we brought some over to share with you!
Oh! Thank you.
These are from Yomogi Nursery!
Oh, thank you!
Here are some potatoes!
Thanks!
They're from Yomogi Nursery!
Fujimoto?
What?
Just a little more and we'll have
delivered all the potatoes, won't we?
Yeah.
Oh!
Oh, look who's back.
Welcome back.
Hello!
Oh!
Little miss, it's been a while since I've seen you, hasn't it!
Yes!
Milk, have you been doing well?
You've gotten a little bigger, haven't you?
He has, he has.
He's been doing wonderfully.
That kid...
Hm?
He was just walking by and
asked to borrow the water faucet.
He said he had just gone potato picking.
You!
You're the one from before!
Hold this!
Wait up!
I told you to wait up!
Let go of me, you thief!
That's my line!
You potato thief.
Put me down!
Fujimoto!
What are you doing?
Taking this thief to the police box.
No! No, don't!
I'll return them! I'll return them, okay?!
Well, would you look at that.
Are you running away from home?
Running away from home?
Your name?
Nothing to say this time, huh?
What's your name?
Potato Thief is fine.
I'm not a Potato Thief!
You have your own name, don't you?
Keita.
Hm?
Why did you run away from home, Keita?
I wanted to go back to my previous home...
Your... previous home?
The house we lived in before. Mom
changed jobs, so we had to move...
So how was your previous home?
I haven't gotten there yet.
Hm?
Is that where you're headed to now?
I really wanted to go, but...
You've forgotten where it is, haven't you?
Have not!
Nope, your face clearly says that you've forgotten.
It does not!
You wouldn't forget something like that, right?
I mean... when we moved,
I was still in kindergarten...
I've just gotten a little confused.
That's called forgetting.
I haven't forgotten!
Keita!
Huh?
If you can tell us what kind of house it was, we might be able to help you look for it!
Would you be able to draw a picture of your house?
Yeah! I can!
Um, you see?
Um...
It had a red roof, and there were windows here and here...
And there was an antenna here... and also...
Draw what was around your house too, okay?
It'll make our search easier!
Um... there was a postbox here,
and next door, there was a dog...
What a big dog!
Every time I walked by, it would bark.
Hm?
Keita Yoshimura
Oh, and also!
Mom would always bake snacks for me...
Wow!
...read picture books to me, take me camping or to the amusement park when she had time off...
Keita?
I want to go back to that house!
Fujimoto!
What?
I... want to help Keita find his house!
With only a postbox and a dog as
leads, there's no way we could find it.
You don't remember anything else?
Huh?
Which way is it? Right? Left?
Um... this way?
Or no, this way!
I know this spot!
I've been here before!
Is that so?
We might be close then.
That's great, isn't it, Keita?
Yeah!
Do you want a drink?
On second thought, I'm okay.
I need to save up.
Save up?
That's a pretty complex term you know.
Cause Mom says it a lot.
I've got it.
Fujimoto?
Huh?
Please take one.
Those are...
Pears.
You can tell just by looking, can't you?
Here.
Is this okay?
We'll leave this in exchange.
Yummy!
It's good.
Fujimoto has his good points too, doesn't he?
I mean...
If he didn't that would be a problem...
Gimme a pear too!
Delish!
Could it be...
This is the dog?
Which means...
Next to this is...
This... isn't my house.
Yoshimura
We're going in.
Watch out.
My room...
It's locked, isn't it?
I guess we have no choice then but to break it.
Fujimoto!
Please!
Don't break it...
You don't want to go back to the house you live in now?
Because... well, Grandpa's there.
Grandfather?
Yeah.
Mom and I... we're living at Grandpa's house right now.
Do you dislike your Grandfather, Keita?
I mean, he's a really big bully...
Bully...
Huh?
Like...
In the morning, he always
yells at me really loudly to get up.
Keita! You aren't up yet?!
Hurry up and tidy that up!
At night, I want to watch just a little more TV...
And play some more games!
Huh?
Keita!
Grandpa, what are you doing?!
No staying up late! Hurry up and get to bed!
And he always makes me eat the things I hate...
Things you hate?
Like small fish and vegetables.
Keita!
Don't play with your food! Eat it!
Is that... bullying?
Yeah! Grandpa hates me!
That's why he's always so strict with me.
He thinks that it would be better if I just left!
That's why I don't want to... go to that house...
Keita...
Miss Sayaka also often tells the kids at the Nursery to eat fish and vegetables
because they're nutritious.
Who's Miss Sayaka?
Miss Sayaka is a kind teacher at Yomogi Nursery who loves all of the children there very much.
Kind?
Keita!
If you're done with your bath, hurry up and go to bed!
Bullying or not... it's hard to tell the difference.
But if you look real closely, you might be able to tell.
Keita.
Were you going to bake potatoes here?
Before, when we all baked potatoes together, it was a lot of fun.
Take some responsibility and take some of these home with you.
What?
I apologized to the lady at the farm for you.
She picked too many potatoes and now we don't know what to do with the leftovers.
That works out well for you, doesn't it, Keita?
Yeah.
Yomogi Station
Can you really get back all by yourself?
I'll be fine, don't worry!
Keita!
Grandpa...
See?
Grandpa!
Keita!
Ow!
What are you doing, old man?!
Don't make me worry like that, you idiot!
Come, we're going home!
Okay.
Your Mom's waiting at home for you too.
Right!
Keita is just about to get on the train with his Grandfather right now.
Oh, no need. Goodbye.
Fujimoto, you know Keita's home phone number?
Were you the one who called Keita's Grandfather?
Who knows.
Anyway, I'm hungry.
Oh...
Let's steam some potatoes when we get back.
Um... okay.
What is it?
It's nothing.
Huh?
Good evening!
Domoto!
Are you guys going home now?
I've got something I need to do, so I'll be going ahead.
Huh?
Something to do?
We went potato picking with the Nursery today.
And so we went to share the potatoes with the neighbors.
I see.
Fujimoto really is...
a nice guy, isn't he?
Yeah, Kiyokazu's a good guy.
I bet this one is from that kid.
But Keita looked really sad looking at his old house...
But then he was able to
understand his Grandfather's feelings.
I see.
Well, Fujimoto also worked really hard today,
so I'll split 100 between
the two of you. 50 points!
Huh?
But Fujimoto was a bully this morning, and...
I suppose that's true...
Well, then taking that into
account, Fujimoto gets a zero.
And you get a 70 for your efforts!
Erase the other one first
before writing a new score!
You've got a lot of complaints, don't you?
I guess it should be 50 points for you after all!
Just erase the other one first!
Shush!
25 points!
What?!
Are you still unsatisfied?
Then 12.5 points!
My face is all black now...!
Even though we all want to fly,
we're being deceived by gravity.
In reality, everybody can already fly.
The reason why that child looks so sad
might be because she left her shadow somewhere.
If so...
If telling you "Thank you",
or hearing "Thank you" just makes you smile,
then doing those things will make me happy.
And they'll make you happy too.
Don't worry, we're together.
It's mysterious as to why tears roll down
even though I'm happy.
Next
...Concealed Prayer.